rswebsols.com 2019-05-05

# Privacy Policy | RS Web Solutions

Your privacy is important to RS Web Solutions. This privacy statement provides information about the personal information that RS Web Solutions collect, and the ways in which RS Web Solutions uses that personal information.

## Who we are

Our website address is [https://www.rswebsols.com](https://www.rswebsols.com/) & [https://www.rswebsols.org](https://www.rswebsols.org/). Our website name is “RS Web Solutions”.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

RS Web Solutions may collect and use the following kinds of personal information:

  * Information about your use of this website.
  * Information that you provide using for the purpose of registering with the website.
  * Information about transactions carried out over this website.
  * Information that you provide for the purpose of subscribing to the website services.

## Using personal information

RS Web Solutions may use your personal information to:

  * Administer this website.
  * Personalize the website for you.
  * Enable your access to and use of the website services.
  * Publish information about you on the website.
  * Send to you products that you purchase.
  * Supply to you services that you purchase.
  * Send your statements and invoices.
  * Collect payments from you.
  * Send you marketing communications from which you can unsubscribe anytime if you wish.

Where RS Web Solutions discloses your personal information to its agents or sub-contractors for these purposes, the agent or sub-contractor in question will be obligated to use that personal information in accordance with the terms of this privacy statement.

In addition to the disclosures reasonably necessary for the purposes identified elsewhere above, RS Web Solutions may disclose your personal information to the extent that it is required to do so by law, in connection with any legal proceedings or prospective legal proceedings, and in order to establish, exercise or defend its legal rights.

## Securing your data

RS Web Solutions will take reasonable technical and organizational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information. RS Web Solutions will store all the personal information you provide on its secure servers. Information relating to electronic transactions entered into via this website will be protected by encryption technology.

## Cross-border data transfers

Information that RS Web Solutions collects may be stored and processed in and transferred between any of the countries in which RS Web Solutions operates to enable the use of the information in accordance with this privacy policy. In addition, personal information that you submit for publication on the website will be published on the internet and may be available around the world. You agree to such cross-border transfers of personal information.

## Using Cookies in RS Web Solutions Website

Yes, we use cookies and other technologies to ensure everyone who uses RS Web Solutions has the best possible experience. Cookies also help us keep your account safe. By continuing to use our services, you are agreeing to the use of cookies and similar technologies.

#### What are cookies?

A cookie is a text file stored in a user’s web browser on any device they use to access a website that holds information regarding the user’s visit, such as preferences. When the user returns, the browser provides the cookie with the stored information to the site.

#### What cookies are used for?

Cookies are used for adjusting a website’s content to fit a user’s preferences and optimize the website. They store useful information that improves the user’s experience of a website. They are most commonly used for:

  * Storing login information so that a user does not need to re-login on every visit.
  * Recognizing the type of device a user is browsing with and any preferences applied to optimize the website specifically for the device.
  * Creating statistics that help website owners to understand how their users interact with their website, which allows them to improve their structure and content.

#### What types of cookies are used?

There are two types of cookies: persistent cookies and session cookies. Persistent cookies remain on your hard drive for a period of time specified in the cookie’s file parameters or until removed manually. When you return to a website and it requires you to log in again despite previously storing your login information, it is usually because the persistent cookie expired; this helps to increase security while maintaining accessibility.

Session cookies, on the other hand, are used temporarily and expire once the website or browser is closed. They are used to track user activity on a website during a single visit. When a website requires that you verify your age or location once every visit before allowing you to view content and without requiring additional personal details, that is a session cookie at work.

#### Do cookies include personal data?

If there is a need for the collection of personal information, such as for creating accounts, then cookies may store personal information. However, it is required by data protection law that users are informed of the collection of personal data. This data will also be encrypted to render it inaccessible for unauthorized users.

#### Managing cookies

By default, browsers are configured to accept cookies. However, these settings may be changed to block cookies entirely, or to inform the user each time they are used. Detailed information about cookies and the options associated with them are available in each browsers’ settings.

## Advertising

RS Web Solutions use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, telephone number or any personal information) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://networkadvertising.org/).

RS Web Solutions allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our website. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, the subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit [networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).

## Affiliate Marketing

Our website may contain affiliate marketing links, which means we may get paid commission on sales of those products or services we write about. Our editorial content is not influenced by advertisers or affiliate partnerships. This disclosure is provided in accordance with the [Federal Trade Commission’s 16 CFR § 255.5: Guides Concerning the Use of Endorsements and Testimonials in Advertising](http://www.ftc.gov/sites/default/files/attachments/press-releases/ftc-publishes-final-guides-governing-endorsements-testimonials/091005revisedendorsementguides.pdf).

## Updating this statement

RS Web Solutions may update this privacy policy by posting a new version on this website. You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are familiar with any changes.

## Other websites

This website contains links to other websites. RS Web Solutions is not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of any third party.

## Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

## Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

## Contact forms

The contact forms provided on our website to help you to quickly connect with us. We do not share your information with anyone else except you.

## Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

## Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

## Analytics:

We use Google Analytics on our website. You can find all privacy-related information for this here: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/>.

## Who we share your data with

We do not share your information with any 3rd party.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## Source: Easy Digital Downloads

We collect information about you during the checkout process on our store. This information may include but is not limited to, your name, billing address, shipping address, email address, phone number, credit card/payment details and any other details that might be requested from you for the purpose of processing your orders.

Handling this data also allows us to:

  * Send you important account/order/service information.
  * Respond to your queries, refund requests, or complaints.
  * Process payments and to prevent fraudulent transactions. We do this on the basis of our legitimate business interests.
  * Set up and administer your account, provide technical and/or customer support, and to verify your identity.

Additionally, we may also collect the following information:

  * Location and traffic data (including IP address and browser type) if you place an order, or if we need to estimate taxes and shipping costs based on your location.
  * Product pages visited and content viewed while your session is active.
  * Your comments and product reviews if you choose to leave them on our website.
  * Account email/password to allow you to access your account if you have one.
  * If you choose to create an account with us, your name, address, and email address, which will be used to populate the checkout for future orders.

## Source: WP Smush

 _Plugin: Smush_

Note: Smush does not interact with end users on your website. The only input option Smush has is to a newsletter subscription for site admins only. If you would like to notify your users of this in your privacy policy, you can use the information below.

Smush sends images to the WPMU DEV servers to optimize them for web use. This includes the transfer of EXIF data. The EXIF data will either be stripped or returned as it is. It is not stored on the WPMU DEV servers.

Smush uses the Stackpath Content Delivery Network (CDN). Stackpath may store web log information of site visitors, including IPs, UA, referrer, Location and ISP info of site visitors for 7 days. Files and images served by the CDN may be stored and served from countries other than your own. Stackpath’s privacy policy can be found here.

Smush uses a third-party email service (Drip) to send informational emails to the site administrator. The administrator’s email address is sent to Drip and a cookie is set by the service. Only administrator information is collected by Drip.

## Source: Akismet

We collect information about visitors who comment on Sites that use our Akismet anti-spam service. The information we collect depends on how the User sets up Akismet for the Site, but typically includes the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself).

## Contact RS Web Solutions

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or RS Web Solution’s treatment of your personal information, please write to us by email to support[@]rswebsols[.]com.
